<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>

  <RD_GattlingLaser.label>gattling laser</RD_GattlingLaser.label>
  <RD_GattlingLaser.description>A ship's gattling laser, fused to a turret base. Designed for space combat, it is vicious and powerful and has extraordinary range, but as its usual targets are larger than houses it is terribly inaccurate.</RD_GattlingLaser.description>

  <RD_Bullet_GattlingLaser.label>improvised turret bullet</RD_Bullet_GattlingLaser.label>

  <RD_Gun_GattlingLaser.label>Gattling Laser</RD_Gun_GattlingLaser.label>
  <RD_Gun_GattlingLaser.description>Jury-rigged gun attached to a turret.</RD_Gun_GattlingLaser.description>

  <RD_Teleporter.label>teleporter</RD_Teleporter.label>
  <RD_Teleporter.description>A glittertech teleportation panel. It can beam people and animals in from anywhere on the planet, but due to crash damage cannot send.</RD_Teleporter.description>

  <RD_HolographicEmitter.label>holo-emitter</RD_HolographicEmitter.label>
  <RD_HolographicEmitter.description>A holo-Emitter. Used on light, fast ships to simulate useful crew members if they are recovered just after death. The body is destroyed on scanning.</RD_HolographicEmitter.description>

  <RD_PortableGenerator.label>portable generator</RD_PortableGenerator.label>
  <RD_PortableGenerator.description>A portable chemfuel-driven generator with a small power cell, designed for power provision away from home.</RD_PortableGenerator.description>

  <RD_QuestComputerTerminal.label>computerTerminal</RD_QuestComputerTerminal.label>
  <RD_QuestComputerTerminal.description>A computer terminal. Who knows what secrets lie within its sprawling file system?</RD_QuestComputerTerminal.description>

  <RD_OsirisCasket.label>osiris casket</RD_OsirisCasket.label>
  <RD_OsirisCasket.description>An advanced GlitterWorld cryptosleep casket that instructs an army of Luciferium nanites to heal wounds, cure illnesses, reverse ageing and even revive the dead. Though heavy, the AI, which separates it from other caskets, is light and recoverable.</RD_OsirisCasket.description>

  <RD_Stargate.label>stargate</RD_Stargate.label>
  <RD_Stargate.description>A gateway allowing for instant travel to another such device via the folding of spacetime around a contained core of exotic matter. A skiled engineer can collect the exotic matter when deconstructing such a device. Links are one way by nature, and for two gates to be linked, each much redirect to the other in accordance with the physical law of narrative control, described by most leaders in the field as "nonsense".</RD_Stargate.description>

  <RD_WeatherSat.label>weather idol</RD_WeatherSat.label>
  <RD_WeatherSat.description>This strange device seems to read the desires of colonists nearby and change the weather accordingly.</RD_WeatherSat.description>

  <RD_PsionicEmanator.label>war idol</RD_PsionicEmanator.label>
  <RD_PsionicEmanator.description>This device can be used by psychics to broadcast a psychic battle ward, improving allies' concentration and reflexes. It can also broadcast the psychic shock of an animal's death to enemies.</RD_PsionicEmanator.description>


</LanguageData>